Lam Chi Ho, Patrick

Flat 26D, Blk H17, Fu Ming Yuen, Chi Fu Fa Yuen, 17 Chi Fu Road, Pokfulam, HK

Mobile: 852- 97363694

E-mail: lamchiho@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

As a Head of Operations with more than 11-year experience in fund administration and Alternative Products operations, seeking for a competitive opportunity to further develop my career in respect of operations and reporting in the financial services industry, utilizing my professional and analytical skills obtained from education and practical work involvement.

WORKING EXPERIENCE

Elpis Capital Limited

Head of Operations

Operations Manager

Aug 2016 - Current Aug 2015 - Aug 2016

- Oversee daily operations, risk management, finance and infrastructure of the company
- Handle middle office operations such as trades processing, reconciliation and settlement for hedge fund
- Take full responsibility on NAV estimates calculation, daily P&L reporting and risk controls to Portfolio Manager and NAV calculation by fund administrators
- Establish controls and procedures in operation workflow to minimize operational risks
- Monitor reports from Prime brokers and ISDA counterparties such as financing, stock borrow and margins and made recommendations for cost and margin efficiency.
- Liaise with various parties including fund managers, prime brokers, executing brokers, fund administrators, auditors and professional investors.
- Review fund's newsletters, presentations and all marketing material in compliance perspective
- Act as in-house Compliance Officer to monitor investment restriction regularly and ensure all necessary disclosure was filed to HKEx in a timely and accurate manner
- Take lead in fund annual audit and monitor work of external auditors and fund administrators to ensure timely completion of audit
- Liaise with outsourced accountant on the company's management accounts and monitor the liquid capital as required by SFC.
- Prepare Due Diligence questionnaires from potential investors of the fund.
- Responsible for new fund and account setup

HSBC Institutional Trust Services (Asia) Limited

Assistant Vice President **Jul 2013 – Aug 2015 Assistant Manager** Jun 2010 - Jul 2013 **Investor Administration Officer** Dec 2007 - Jun 2010 **Senior Fund Accountant Apr 2007 – Dec 2007 Fund Accountant** Oct 2005 - Apr 2007

- · Lead a team of 6 fund administrators to deliver the core requirements of functions in relation to KYC, AML, Client Due Diligence and investors Subscription, Redemption, etc to all client optimizing effectiveness and efficiency
- Ensure the highest standard of services is delivered consistently to client through pro-active client management
- Monitor cash management function of funds
- Take full responsibility for complex SPV transaction, performance fee calculation, equalization and distribution
- Communicate and coordinate with regulators regarding Audit and regulatory issues.
- · Ensure funds' operational procedures are under tight control by adherence to their fund prospectus, market practices and internal compliance policies to minimize operational issues
- Ensure FATCA reporting requirements are fulfilled in timely and accurate manner
- · Participate in new funds setup & UAT process for new systems and existing system enhancement
- Review department's workflow and procedures for continuous improvement on efficiency and effectiveness
- Take lead in transition project to setup new investor services department in GZ
- Train and provide advices to junior fund administrators on daily operations

Lee and Chow Solicitors

Summer Intern

Jul 2004 - Aug 2004

- Handle daily client inquiries and documentation filings
- Responsible for providing clerical and administration supports in various Accounting functions.
- · Handle ad hoc assessments as required

EDUCATION

The Chinese University of Hong Kong

Master of Accountancy

Sep 2011 - Jun 2012

Postgraduate Diploma in Professional Accountancy Sep 2009 – Jun 2010

Bachelor of Social Science (2nd Lower Class Honours) Sep 2002 – Jun 2005

Major: Financial Economics & Minor: Statistics

Yuen Long Lutheran Secondary School Secondary One to Secondary Seven

Sep 1995 - Jun 2002

- HKALE (A in AL Geography, B in AL Economics)
- HKCEE (Full Certificate with C in Chinese Language, Mathematics & Geography)

QUALIFICATION

SFC Licensed Representative for Type 9 Regulated Activity (CE No. BHY523)

SKILLS

Language Fluent in spoken and written English, Mandarin and Cantonese

Computer skills Imagine Trading System, Automated Workflow Distributors (AWD),

NTAS, Bloomberg, Chinese Word Processing, MS Office